<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on vs206</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on vs206</description>
    <image>
      <title>vs206</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/logo.jpg</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/logo.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.125.7</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 15:52:24 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Guide To Git</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/guidetogit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 15:52:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/guidetogit/</guid>
      <description>This is a practical guide for git, and it is mainly aimed towards the ones who have no idea on what and how to use git. If you know someone who does not know how to use git, share them this article.
What is Git? Git is a fast, scalable, distributed version control system with an unusually rich command set that provides both high-level operations and full access to internals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ebook with Markdown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ebookwithmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 15:52:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ebookwithmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>Pandoc is a great tool for converting a file in one markup format into another. This means we can use it to convert a file written in Markdown into an EPUB file that is supported by many e-readers.
Lets start by writting a very simple markdown file called example_ebook.md.
--- title: - type: main text: Example Ebook - type: subtitle text: An Ebook created from a Markdown file creator: - role: author text: David Sadler publisher: Published by myself --- This is an introduction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Docker Installation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/dockersetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 15:37:27 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/dockersetup/</guid>
      <description>Installing Docker Docker is installed via package manager.
Arch Linux $ sudo pacman -S docker Debian/Ubuntu Linux $ sudo apt-get install docker.io Starting Docker Engine Start the Docker daemon which provides the Docker Engine. This process serves the Docker API and manages Docker containers.
$ sudo systemctl start docker.service If you want Docker Engine to automatically start when you system boots issue the below command.
$ sudo systemctl enable docker.service Verify that Docker Engine is running.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> DWM Setup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/dwmsetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 15:37:27 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/dwmsetup/</guid>
      <description>Installing ST, DMENU and DWM Introduction So Let&amp;rsquo;s Start, we will be require to install two things. A window system of some sort and a layout manager. For this installation I&amp;rsquo;m going with Xorg and dwm. For those that are not aware dwm is dynamic window manager for Xorg that has been developed by Suckless. Since by default dwm expects st to be installed as the system&amp;rsquo;s terminal and also makes use dmenu using which we launch applications I will installed both of them in addition to dwm.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BSPWM Setup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/bspwmsetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 15:37:27 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/bspwmsetup/</guid>
      <description>Installing ST, DMENU, and BSPWM Introduction So Let&amp;rsquo;s Start, we will be installing two things. A window system and a layout manager. For this installation I&amp;rsquo;m using Xorg and bspwm. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know bspwm is tiling window manager for Xorg . we will install st to be our default terminal and also make use of dmenu for launching applications, I will installed both of them in addition to bspwm.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stuff/Resources I use</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/stuff-i-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 15:37:27 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/stuff-i-use/</guid>
      <description>So this is About Stuff/Resources I use.
System I have 2 Laptops:
One is old like from 2014. Its a Lenovo IdeaPad G500 series laptop. My linux testing and Other things which I want to try. And You can say like Server stuff, storing Data are done on this laptop. I upgraded it with a 240gb SATA SSD AND it has 8GB Ram. But a Old Dual core processor which is not good for today&amp;rsquo;s world.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
